ufs.ac.za 2010-09-21

# University of the Free State / Universiteit van die Vrystaat / Yunivesithi Ya Freistata

 |  |  |   
---  
| Tuis |  | Kontak Ons |  | Web uitleg  
|  |   
---  
| Privaatheidsbeleid   
---  
  
#### **Privacy Statement**

Thank you for visiting the website of the University of the Free State (UFS). The privacy of individuals visiting our website is of the utmost importance to us. Please be sure to read this entire Privacy Statement before using or submitting information to this website. Please note that whenever you submit information via this website, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of information in accordance with this Privacy Statement. This Privacy Statement only pertains to the official website of the UFS.

**Collection of Personal Information**

If you are only browsing this website or using the search function, we do not capture data that identifies you or reveals any personal information. The only personal information obtained is personal information voluntarily provided to us by yourself when visiting the website. Please note that you will only be providing personal information when you are required to send a message from the website, fill out a form or questionnaire, or answer questions, in all instances followed by a disclaimer stating that by submission of such information you consent to use of such information by the UFS in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Statement. If you choose to share personal information with the UFS in any other manner, the UFS undertakes to only use such information for responding to an enquiry or other requests for information or for other purposes you have authorized, unless your consent has been obtained or otherwise required by law.

**Collection of Technical Information**

Technical information refers to information that does not by itself identify a specific individual. As you navigate through our website, certain technical information may be passively collected by the web server of the UFS through making use of “cookies” and/or “server logs”. 

> **Cookies:            **A cookie is a file that is stored on your hard drive and which contains information about the preferences that you have expressed during previous visits to the website. Cookies help us personalize your online experience. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually refuse cookies, or selectively accept certain cookies, by adjusting the preferences in your browser settings. **** Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personal information while you are browsing this website. 
> 
> **Server logs:     **The UFS may use server logs to collect information concerning your internet connection and general information about your visit to this website. This information may be used to analyze trends; to create summary statistics for the purpose of determining technical design specifications; and to identify system performance or problem areas.

**Disclosure of Information**

All personal information submitted or provided by you will be treated confidentially and the UFS will not sell, rent, lease or disclose your personal information to others. The UFS shall only disclose your personal information after obtaining your consent or if required to do so by law.

**Security**

To safeguard your personal data, all electronic storage and transmission of personal information are secured with appropriate security technologies and policies. The UFS will furthermore use all reasonable endeavours to ensure the integrity, security and confidentiality of all personal information submitted and/or obtained from you, subject to the provisor that no data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure and the UFS cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to or from this website, and you do so at you own risk. The UFS will not be held liable under any circumstances if such information is compromised, disseminated or otherwise disclosed through conduct outside the control of the UFS such as hacking, infection by viruses, Trojan Horses or any other computer programming routines or software that are intended to damage, detrimentally interfere with, surreptitiously intercept or expropriate any system, data or personal information.

**Links**

This website contains links to other websites operated and maintained by third parties. The UFS is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. These links are provided for convenience and do not imply endorsement by the UFS or any acceptance of their content. You should always read the privacy policy of a linked website before using the linked site or disclosing any personal information on such website.

**Changes to policy**

The UFS reserves the right to change, amend or update this policy periodically. The UFS will update this Privacy Statement continually to ensure that you are aware of developments in this area. We will post those changes here so that you will always know what information we collect online, how we use it, and what choices you have in this regard.

**Contact us**

The UFS welcomes your comments and questions regarding this Privacy Statement, the practices of this website or your dealings with this website. You can contact the UFS webmaster at [webmaster@mail.uovs.ac.za](mailto:webmaster@mail.uovs.ac.za)  
  
|  |   
---|---
